vermontcountrystore.com 2002-12-01

# The Vermont Country Store - Security Policy

Privacy Statement For "http://www.vermontcountrystore.com"

The Vermont Country Store has created this privacy statement in order to demonstrate our firm commitment to privacy and to the protection of the information we ask you to give us.

The following discloses our information gathering and dissemination practices for this website: http://www.vermontcountrystore.com.

How We Use Your IP Address  
Your Shopper ID  
Cookies  
Contact Information  
Links To Other Web Sites  
Our On-Line Order Form  
Sharing Information You Provide Us With Third Parties  
Public Forums  
Security  
Choice / Opt-Out  
Correct / Update  
Contacting The Web Site  

How We Use Your IP address

We use your IP address to help diagnose problems with our server, and to administer our Web site. Your IP address is used to help identify you and your shopping cart.

Your Shopper ID

Our site assigns you a unique shopper identification code. We use this code to:

  * identify the items in your shopping cart
  * identify you when you return to our site and as you move through different pages on our site
  * identify your order in our order processing system

We may aggregate information about the pages you visit with information about the pages that other shoppers visit. In doing this, we do not associate the contact information you supply us with your shopper identification.

Cookies

Our site uses cookies to keep track of your shopping cart. We use cookies to deliver content specific to your interests and to save your password so you don't have to reenter it each time you visit our site.

Cookies are not required to browse our site but they are required to place an order.

If you prefer not to turn on cookies to shop this site, we invite you to browse the site and place items in the shopping basket that you wish to purchase. Before you check out, you may print the page that lists your order and: 

  * Call us at 1-802-362-8460 to place your order 
    * Mon - Fri: 7:00am to Midnight Eastern Time
    * Sat - Sun: 8:00am to 8:00pm Eastern Time
    * Other hours: Please leave your order on our telephone answering system

  * Fax your order to: 1-802-362-0285  

  * Mail your order to: 

> The Vermont Country Store Mail Order Office  
>  P.O. Box 3000  
>  Manchester Center, VT 05255-3000 

When placing your order, please have your payment information ready or enclose it with your order.

Contact Information 

Our site's registration form requires users to give us contact information (such as their name and email address). The customer's contact information is used to contact the visitor when necessary. Occasionally, we may make your contact information available to other reputable companies that offer products or services that we think may interest you. These companies may use this information to solicit you to purchase their products or services. Users may opt-out of receiving future mailings from the Vermont Country Store or opt out from having their names supplied to others; see the choice/opt-out section below.

We may also use your contact information and information about the products you purchase and may aggregate it with other shopper's personal information in order to identify specific purchasing trends or purchasing patterns.

Links to Other Web Sites

This site contains links to other sites. Please note that http://www.vermontcountrystore.com is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such Web sites.

Our On-Line Order Form

Our site uses an order form for customers to request information, products, and services. We collect visitor's contact information (like their email address) and financial information (like their credit card numbers) as part of our order form. Contact information from the order form is used to send orders and information about our company to our customers. The customer's contact information is also used to get in touch with the visitor when necessary.

Occasionally, we may make your contact information available to other reputable companies that offer products or services that we think may interest you. These companies may use this information to solicit you to purchase their products or services. 

Users may elect to be excluded from receiving future mailings from the Vermont Country Store and users may elect to have their names supplied to others. For additional information, please see the choice/opt-out section below.

We may also use your contact information and information about the products you purchase and may aggregate it with other shopper's personal information in order to identify specific purchasing trends or purchasing patterns.

Financial information (such as credit card numbers) that is collected on the order form is used to bill the user for products and services. We do not store credit card numbers or expiration dates on this web site and do not aggregate credit card information with any other information we may collect on the site. 

For security reasons, we ask you to enter a credit card number each time you place an order with us.

Sharing Information You Provide Us With Third Parties

The personal information you have provided us and information about your order may be shared with third parties. This information may be combined with other personally identifiable information (such as demographic information and past purchases information) available from our records and other sources. This information will be used to make our future marketing efforts more efficient. It may also be used by our marketing partners to bring you offers of interest. To learn more about our marketing partner, click [here](http://www.plazadirect.com/index.cfm?main=privacy&ccsyn=186).

If you prefer that we do not share your name and address with marketing partners, please email us at [this address](mailto:customerservice@vermontcountrystore.com).

If you agreed to receive email from our marketing partners, we will share with them your email address and the information described above, so they can send you offers for products and services that may be of interest to you. We will only share your email address if you have opted in by checking the appropriate box.

Additionally, each email our partners send you will include a description of the simple opt-out process to enable you to stop receiving future emails.

Public Forums

This site makes chat rooms, forums, message boards, and/or news groups available to its users. Please remember that any information that is disclosed in these areas becomes public information and you should exercise caution when deciding to disclose your personal information. The Vermont Country Store reserves the right to monitor these chat rooms, forums, message boards and/or news groups and remove items and postings that we deem are slanderous, false, misleading or damaging to the purpose of the public forum.

Security

This site has security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse and alteration of the information under our control. We do not store credit card numbers on our site.

To protect your credit card numbers, we require you to enter your credit card information each time you place an order with us. All transaction information that you supply to us from your browser is exchanged with our server using a secure hypertext protocol. This protects information from compromise as it travels between your computer and our Web server. Contact information (such as your name, address and telephone) that you supply us is stored in a secured database on our server or on our order processing system.

| You can verify the status of the certificate we use to encrypt your transaction and credit-card information by clicking on the logo. |   
---|---  
  
Choice/Opt-Out

Our site provides users the opportunity to either elect to or elect not to receive communications from us and our partners at the point where we request information about the visitor. This site gives users the following options for removing their information from our database or for electing not to receive future communications from us:

  1. You can send email to [customerservice@vermontcountrystore.com](mailto:customerservice@vermontcountrystore.com?subject=Your%20Mailing%20List%20\(E004\))
  2. You can visit this page and update your membership profile  
  3. You can call the following telephone number: **1-802-362-8460**
  4. You can send mail to the following postal address:

> The Vermont Country Store  
>  Attn: Mailing List Maintenance  
>  5650 Main Street  
>  P.O. Box 1108  
>  Manchester Center, VT 05255-1108

When contacting us about changing and modifying your contact information, please include your customer number from a recent order form and a copy of your contact information from a recent communication with us.

Correct/Update

This site gives users the following options for changing and modifying information previously provided.

  1. You can send email to [customerservice@vermontcountrystore.com](mailto:privacy@vermontcountrystore.com?subject=Your%20Mailing%20List%20\(E004\))
  2. You can visit this page and update your membership profile
  3. You can call the following telephone number: **1-802-362-8460**
  4. You can send mail to the following postal address:

> The Vermont Country Store  
>  Attn: Mailing List Maintenance  
>  5650 Main Street  
>  P.O. Box 1108  
>  Manchester Center, VT 05255-1108 USA

When contacting us about changing and modifying your contact information, please include your customer number from a recent order form and a copy of your contact information from a recent communication with us.

Contacting the Web Site

If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this Web site, you can contact

Director, Electronic Commerce   
The Vermont Country Store  
5650 Main Street  
P.O. Box 1108  
Manchester Center, VT 05255-1108 USA  
Email: [customerservice@vermontcountrystore.com](mailto:customerservice@vermontcountystore.com?subject=Security%20Policy%20\(E004\))
